<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blue Water</title>
    <link>/services/boss/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Blue Water</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/services/boss/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>/services/boss/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/boss/intro/</guid>
      <description>Optimum voyage planning and monitoring can save upto 10% fuel in a voyage. BOSS seamlessly encompasses a number of related services to make this possible. BOSS combines data models with advanced optimization algorithms to plan a voyage with intelligent weather routing and dynamic speed scheduling. Planning is where things just get started. Automatic data logging through our accelerated noon reporting system creates a complete fleet management toolkit for voyage monitoring, vessel performance analysis, bunker claims management and much more!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIRROR</title>
      <link>/services/boss/s_mirror/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/boss/s_mirror/</guid>
      <description>BOSS uses MIRROR for accelerated and validated vessel noon reporting. Noon report data serves as the basis for all post voyage reports and voyage performance analysis, in commercial shipping operations. BOSS ensures this data goes through several layers of validation before any critical decisions are made using it.
An interactive, vessel specific HTML form is sent out to the vessel which has several client side validations to prevent erroneous data entry at the very source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimization</title>
      <link>/services/boss/s_optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/boss/s_optimization/</guid>
      <description>A bar headed Goose may lose up to 3 pounds in its flight from Central Asia to South Asia. A voyage like this requires significant planning to reach the destination in the given time using the minimum possible resources. BOSS aims to optimize main engine fuel consumption through optimum voyage planning and monitoring. A weather foresight across the entire route space when used by a smart algorithm can help decide a route and a speed schedule that optimizes the fuel consumption for just in time arrival at the destination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance Trending</title>
      <link>/services/boss/s_performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/boss/s_performance/</guid>
      <description>BOSS goes beyond voyage planning and management! The validated noon data combined with analyzed weather is used for deriving insights about vessel performance which can assist vessel operators to take decisions about hull cleaning, engine and propeller maintenance.
Our data-analytics toolkit analyzes the relationships between engine load, fuel consumption, RPM and speed to understand the current and historic vessel performance trend. Read more to understand how we normalize our data to compare vessels across the fleet on a common scale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voyage Management</title>
      <link>/services/boss/s_management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/boss/s_management/</guid>
      <description>While optimum voyage planning is a smart first step for saving bunkers, a transparent data visualization and alerting system is essential to monitor the compliance of a voyage plan to ensure that the bunker savings are realized during the voyage.
BOSS serves as an single platform that combines data from several data sources including noon reports, SAT-AIS positions and weather forecasts to provide tools that bring voyage management at your fingertips.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>