<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blue Water</title><link>/services/chm/</link><description>Recent content on Blue Water</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/services/chm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CHAMP (Cargo Heating Advanced Marine Process)</title><link>/services/chm/s_champ/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/services/chm/s_champ/</guid><description>CHAMP is an interactive and secure web application which allows our esteemed clients to access data of heated cargo voyages enrolled under Cargo Heating Management Service. It assists users to monitor/ compare their voyages at different levels of abstraction.</description></item><item><title>Cargo Heating Apportioned Log Service</title><link>/services/chm/s_aportion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/services/chm/s_aportion/</guid><description>Cargo Heating Apportioned Log Service(CHAL) splits consumption logically and reasonably between Owners and Charterers in the case of cargo heat up. This application was devised to scientifically segregate per day consumption between grade(s) duly taking into account cargo quantity, temperature, and ambient conditions.
Blue Water, through a customized application, splits the consumptions billable into reasonable Heat Up and Maintain fractions. This service supports the vessel manager in voyage P/L calculations and also avoids expensive claims or disputes among the stakeholders.</description></item><item><title>Cargo Heating Management</title><link>/services/chm/s_chm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/services/chm/s_chm/</guid><description>Penguins are a warm-blooded animal of cold climate. They survive in coldest and harshest climate on earth, where they can be the only animals there. It is rightly said that animal’s body is best living machine on earth. The Blue Water team was inspired by this animal and applied a derivative philosophy to shipping through our service, which targets energy conservation. Cargo Heating Management Service aims to optimize boiler consumption on cargo heating through proper planning and monitoring of cargo heating operations onboard to assist the vessel staff and voyage operators.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>/services/chm/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/services/chm/intro/</guid><description>Cargo Heating Management Service aims to optimize boiler consumption on cargo heating through proper planning and monitoring of cargo heating operations onboard to assist the vessel staff and voyage operators. Having managed more than 4000 cargo heating voyages managed till date, Blue Water pioneers in providing a data-driven solution to optimum cargo heating management.</description></item></channel></rss>