<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Index on Blue Water</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Index on Blue Water</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 16:28:15 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Because BOSS needs an assistant</title>
      <link>/blog/qaira/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 16:28:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/qaira/</guid>
      <description>Blue Water is excited to announce the release of Qaira – Query and information retrieval agent. Qaira (pronounced as Kyra) is a smart and intuitive virtual assistant, that provides data driven answers to questions regarding your fleet. With BOSS digesting data from various sources each minute, Qaira offers an intelligent interface that can analyze data in real time and deliver information useful for decision making.
Digitization and automation are the future of the shipping industry and we at Blue Water strive to stay a step ahead in this ever evolving industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying Fuel Savings</title>
      <link>/blog/benchmarking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 16:28:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/benchmarking/</guid>
      <description>With increasing fuel prices and environmental awareness, maximizing energy efficiency is one of the highest priorities in voyage planning. Various weather routing algorithms have shown great potential in optimizing main engine fuel consumption while ensuring safe navigation. However, quantifying the fuel savings achieved by using these services remains a major challenge in the marine industry. The lack of a transparent and logical benchmarking system for comparing fuel consumption with and without engaging a fuel optimization service is the main roadblock in calculating fuel savings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voyage Optimization- Complete, Reliable &amp; Accurate</title>
      <link>/blog/voyage-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 16:28:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/voyage-optimization/</guid>
      <description>Fuel optimization is a much talked about topic these days, but not many feasible steps have been taken to incorporate it into practice. Blue Water’s small step forward in optimizing fuel oil consumption in cargo heating has made a large impact in terms of fuel oil savings realized in this domain.
Bluewater Optimum speed services (BOSS) is an environment-friendly initiative having focused on energy conservation. BOSS assures fuel savings of around 8-10% on the main engine without compromising with an arrival time of the vessel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/main_page_content/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/main_page_content/intro/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/main_page_content/team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/main_page_content/team/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Us</title>
      <link>/main_page_content/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/main_page_content/about/</guid>
      <description>Blue Water focuses on maritime energy efficiency areas, harnessing the experience of its professionals from diverse industries. These services are milestone addition to the upcoming ways of saving fossil fuels and reducing environmental impact from emissions; primarily by innovating new methodologies to optimize the fuel consumption across diverse operations.
Emerging technologies like artificial intelligence, deep learning, and faster computational resources are offering plenty of opportunities to accelerate the digital transformation of the shipping industry, yielding results which are significantly superior to both, traditional management and purely data-driven methodologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cargo Heating Apportioned Log Service</title>
      <link>/services/chm/s_aportion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/chm/s_aportion/</guid>
      <description>Cargo Heating Apportioned Log Service(CHAL) splits consumption logically and reasonably between Owners and Charterers in the case of cargo heat up. This application was devised to scientifically segregate per day consumption between grade(s) duly taking into account cargo quantity, temperature, and ambient conditions.
Blue Water, through a customized application, splits the consumptions billable into reasonable Heat Up and Maintain fractions. This service supports the vessel manager in voyage P/L calculations and also avoids expensive claims or disputes among the stakeholders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cargo Heating Management</title>
      <link>/services/chm/s_chm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/chm/s_chm/</guid>
      <description>Penguins are a warm-blooded animal of cold climate. They survive in coldest and harshest climate on earth, where they can be the only animals there. It is rightly said that animal’s body is best living machine on earth. The Blue Water team was inspired by this animal and applied a derivative philosophy to shipping through our service, which targets energy conservation. Cargo Heating Management Service aims to optimize boiler consumption on cargo heating through proper planning and monitoring of cargo heating operations onboard to assist the vessel staff and voyage operators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHAMP (Cargo Heating Advanced Marine Process)</title>
      <link>/services/chm/s_champ/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/chm/s_champ/</guid>
      <description>CHAMP is an interactive and secure web application which allows our esteemed clients to access data of heated cargo voyages enrolled under Cargo Heating Management Service. It assists users to monitor/ compare their voyages at different levels of abstraction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clients</title>
      <link>/main_page_content/clients/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/main_page_content/clients/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>/services/boss/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/boss/intro/</guid>
      <description>Optimum voyage planning and monitoring can save upto 10% fuel in a voyage. BOSS seamlessly encompasses a number of related services to make this possible. BOSS combines data models with advanced optimization algorithms to plan a voyage with intelligent weather routing and dynamic speed scheduling. Planning is where things just get started. Automatic data logging through our accelerated noon reporting system creates a complete fleet management toolkit for voyage monitoring, vessel performance analysis, bunker claims management and much more!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>/services/chm/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/chm/intro/</guid>
      <description>Cargo Heating Management Service aims to optimize boiler consumption on cargo heating through proper planning and monitoring of cargo heating operations onboard to assist the vessel staff and voyage operators. Having managed more than 4000 cargo heating voyages managed till date, Blue Water pioneers in providing a data-driven solution to optimum cargo heating management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media</title>
      <link>/main_page_content/media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/main_page_content/media/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media</title>
      <link>/main_page_content/stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/main_page_content/stats/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIRROR</title>
      <link>/services/boss/s_mirror/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/boss/s_mirror/</guid>
      <description>BOSS uses MIRROR for accelerated and validated vessel noon reporting. Noon report data serves as the basis for all post voyage reports and voyage performance analysis, in commercial shipping operations. BOSS ensures this data goes through several layers of validation before any critical decisions are made using it.
An interactive, vessel specific HTML form is sent out to the vessel which has several client side validations to prevent erroneous data entry at the very source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimization</title>
      <link>/services/boss/s_optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/boss/s_optimization/</guid>
      <description>A bar headed Goose may lose up to 3 pounds in its flight from Central Asia to South Asia. A voyage like this requires significant planning to reach the destination in the given time using the minimum possible resources. BOSS aims to optimize main engine fuel consumption through optimum voyage planning and monitoring. A weather foresight across the entire route space when used by a smart algorithm can help decide a route and a speed schedule that optimizes the fuel consumption for just in time arrival at the destination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Journey</title>
      <link>/team/s_journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/team/s_journey/</guid>
      <description>From Dairy farming to commodity trading to cargo heating management service to a full fledged Marine Software as service provider today- The journey of our company has been more than just challenging and exciting. Blue Water Trade Winds Pvt. Ltd, as the name may suggest, was incorporated by fellow mariners in year 2006 for carrying out large scale commodity trading. It took us almost two years to realize that Trade Winds only assist a vessel at sea but not an organization in Dehradun (India) at the foothills of Himalayas, thousands of miles away from sea!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance Trending</title>
      <link>/services/boss/s_performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/boss/s_performance/</guid>
      <description>BOSS goes beyond voyage planning and management! The validated noon data combined with analyzed weather is used for deriving insights about vessel performance which can assist vessel operators to take decisions about hull cleaning, engine and propeller maintenance.
Our data-analytics toolkit analyzes the relationships between engine load, fuel consumption, RPM and speed to understand the current and historic vessel performance trend. Read more to understand how we normalize our data to compare vessels across the fleet on a common scale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Services</title>
      <link>/main_page_content/services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/main_page_content/services/</guid>
      <description>Being a full-fledged maritime service provider, Blue Water strongly believes in promoting a greener planet by keeping a pollution free marine environment as one of its important goals. We take it as our responsibility to ensure that all our endeavors constantly focus on contributing towards reducing harmful emissions, fossil fuel consumption and any other forms of marine pollution. Our services are coherent with our company’s innate philosophy of providing cost-effective eco-tech services and solutions to Transportation, Energy and Maritime industries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voyage Management</title>
      <link>/services/boss/s_management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/boss/s_management/</guid>
      <description>While optimum voyage planning is a smart first step for saving bunkers, a transparent data visualization and alerting system is essential to monitor the compliance of a voyage plan to ensure that the bunker savings are realized during the voyage.
BOSS serves as an single platform that combines data from several data sources including noon reports, SAT-AIS positions and weather forecasts to provide tools that bring voyage management at your fingertips.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>