<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Blue Water</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Blue Water</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 16:28:15 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>LNG Voyage Optimization with BOSS</title>
      <link>/blog/lng/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 16:28:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/lng/</guid>
      <description>Over the years, voyage optimization for LNG carriers has been limited to just weather routing. However, to fully exploit the scope of LNG optimization, it is crucial to strike the right balance between boil-off rate, speed, course and commercial factors. With more than 650 LNG carriers operating globally and hire rates soaring to as high as $500K per day, LNG voyage optimization is more imperative than ever before.
BOSS provides an optimization solution to exploit factors outside our control by controlling factors which are in our control</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultranav’s Cape Tankers Opts BOSS Optimisation Suite for Fleet Optimisation &amp; Decarbonization </title>
      <link>/blog/contract_capetankers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 16:28:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/contract_capetankers/</guid>
      <description>Cape Tankers, an Ultranav group company, and Indian maritime technology company, BlueWater Trade Winds, announced the official signing of their contract to implement BlueWater’s “BOSS Voyage Optimisation Suite” for their Panamax and Aframax fleet.
The BOSS Suite will serve as a catalyst to Cape Tankers’ decarbonisation strategy, which includes energy efficiency, intelligent voyage optimization, efficient fleet management, weather routing, and vessel performance analysis.
Capt. Ruben Aaros , General Manager Operations, Cape Tankers said: “Choosing BOSS Suite for our fleet was a natural choice since during the trials, we observed a positive influence of BOSS modus operandi on our voyage operations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Vessel Operations Future Ready: Blue Water Rolls Out BOSS CII Estimator</title>
      <link>/blog/cii-estimator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 16:28:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/cii-estimator/</guid>
      <description>Carbon Intensity Indicator (CII) has been the complex burning topic in the maritime industry. Since the announcement, there have been numerous debates regarding the compliance measures yet with just 5 months to go, about 75% of vessels will not be EEXI compliant according to a report from VesselsValue.
There’s no doubt that the early movers will have a better CII rating that would have a direct impact on vessel employment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimize Voyages Like It’s 2022, Because It Is!</title>
      <link>/blog/voyage-optimisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 16:28:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/voyage-optimisation/</guid>
      <description>For the past several years, the scope of voyage optimization has been limited to weather routing and weather advisory for a given sea passage. Seasoned mariners and meteorologists, with the help of a route search algorithm advise a route that minimizes bad weather exposure while maintaining a reasonable ship speed until the destination. This approach however, oversimplifies a rather complex problem and can lead to suboptimal fuel savings, weather damages and breach of commercial obligations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oldendorff inks a contract with Blue Water for Voyage Optimisation</title>
      <link>/blog/contract_od/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 16:28:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/contract_od/</guid>
      <description>Oldendorff Inks a contract with Blue Water for Voyage Optimisation and Fleet Decarbonization by implementing BOSS after a Year-long trial.  The largest German bulk carrier company, Oldendorff Carriers, and India-headquartered maritime technology company, Blue Water, announced the official signing of their contract to implement Blue Water’s “BOSS Voyage Optimisation Suite” for Oldendorff’s Cape &amp;amp; Baby Cape fleet of owned and time chartered vessels. The BOSS Suite will propel Oldendorff’s continuous efforts towards a greener maritime trade by reducing emissions through intelligent voyage optimization, weather routing, vessel performance analysis and efficient fleet management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vessel Performance Monitoring </title>
      <link>/blog/performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 16:28:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/performance/</guid>
      <description>Performance monitoring solutions can provide valuable insights for making decisions such as hull cleaning, propeller polishing, vessel rehiring, and associated negotiations. With the ongoing digitalization of the shipping industry, data is available in abundance for building performance analysis tools. However, drawing actionable insights from such data can be challenging. Existing performance monitoring solutions fall short because of the following reasons:
“The differentiating factor between various performance monitoring solutions is not the machine learning algorithm how the system deals with the inputs and outputs of the algorithm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage and Optimize Marine Emissions with BOSS</title>
      <link>/blog/ciiscc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 16:28:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/ciiscc/</guid>
      <description>The marine industry is aligning its efforts to promote international shipping decarbonization. The International Maritime Organization (IMO) has set an ambitious goal to reduce shipping&amp;rsquo;s total annual Greenhouse Gas emissions by at least 50% by 2050. As a first step to achieving this goal, IMO has introduced a standard metric for the current emission efficiency of ships called the Annual Emission Ratio (AER). AER measures the emission efficiency in terms of grams of CO2 emitted per cargo-carrying capacity and distance sailed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BOSS 2021 Rewind</title>
      <link>/blog/2021rewind/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 16:28:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021rewind/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Because BOSS needs an assistant</title>
      <link>/blog/qaira/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 16:28:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/qaira/</guid>
      <description>Blue Water is excited to announce the release of Qaira – Query and information retrieval agent. Qaira (pronounced as Kyra) is a smart and intuitive virtual assistant, that provides data driven answers to questions regarding your fleet. With BOSS digesting data from various sources each minute, Qaira offers an intelligent interface that can analyze data in real time and deliver information useful for decision making.
Digitization and automation are the future of the shipping industry and we at Blue Water strive to stay a step ahead in this ever evolving industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying Fuel Savings</title>
      <link>/blog/benchmarking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 16:28:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/benchmarking/</guid>
      <description>With increasing fuel prices and environmental awareness, maximizing energy efficiency is one of the highest priorities in voyage planning. Various weather routing algorithms have shown great potential in optimizing main engine fuel consumption while ensuring safe navigation. However, quantifying the fuel savings achieved by using these services remains a major challenge in the marine industry. The lack of a transparent and logical benchmarking system for comparing fuel consumption with and without engaging a fuel optimization service is the main roadblock in calculating fuel savings.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>